

Katowice, ul. Fijewskiego 5



artur@gurgul.pro



https://artur.gurgul.pro

SKILLS

- SwiftUI
- UIKit
- RxSwift
- Combine Framework
- Swift
- · Objective-C
- CoreData
- CoreAnimation
- · Agile Scrum/Kanban
- CI/Jenkins
- JIRA and devOps
- Cocoapods
- Node.js

LANGUAGE

- Polish (native)
- English (B2)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of science, PWSZ, Tarnów Information Technology

October 2006 - November 2011

ARTUR GURGUL

SOFTWARE ENGINEER



PROFILE

I'm a passionate iOS developer with about 10 years of experience who isn't afraid of challenges. I'm also working every day on myself to be better as a person and as a software developer.

I am constantly curious about new technologies in order to keep myself updated.

I like to share my knowledge with others and I find discussing new ideas very interesting.



EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

tvOS Developer at Redge Sp. z o. o., Remote/Katowice

July 2022 - Present

I am working on a VOD platform on tvOS. My responsibility is to develop and fix errors on version for TVP VOD and CKF Warszawa. We are working in git flow, focusing on the code quality and giving constructive feedback.

Used: MVVM-C, UIKit, Swift, JIRA, Cocoapods, SPM, Kanban, Combine

iOS Developer at Alten, Remote/Katowice

July 2022 - November 2022

I was working on the iOS banking application for NatWest. The application is using a very complex architecture that was designed by the Backbase experts.

My main responsibility was to fix the bugs. I got experience working in a very large team that was divided into many "squads".

Used: Custom architecture, UIKit, Swift, JIRA, Codoapods, JFrog, Scrum

iOS Developer at Vattenfall, Katowice

April 2017 - June 2022

I worked there on a very interesting and innovative project which aims at EV drivers. My main responsibility was to create new features and fix bugs. The app oryginalny has been written in Objective-C using UIKit. I improved the architecture and introduced SwiftUI and Combine Framework. Moreover I was involved in research and I often took part in "brain storm" regarding user experience.

I also created a small internal project for booking parking spots. When I started a job here we used a spreadsheet for it. Me and a colleague came up with the idea for a mobile app. In this project I designed the API and implemented it using Node Js running in the Azure environment.

Used: MS devOps, MVVM, RxSwift/Combine, Agile/Scrum, Cocoa pods, JS, Nodejs, SwiftUI, Azure, Firebase.

iOS Developer at RST IT, Wrocław

May 2016 - October 2016

RST IT is a software house where I was responsible for developing the app named Zbooni. The product is dedicated to sellers who offer their products using social networks like Facebook. My responsibility was to develop the application according to the specification provided by the client. The project was running Agile methodology where the client actively participated with feedback.

Used: CI/GreenHouse, JIRA, MVVM, RxSwift, Agile/Kanban, Cocoa pods

iOS Developer at SMSgrupp, Stockholm

October 2013 - November 2015

SMSgrupp is a single product company where I worked on a SMS system named Supertext. I was responsible for fixing the bugs and publishing the application. I had rewritten the code from Objc to Swift. Here I had a lot of opportunities to discuss the project and affect how the application would work. We planned very carefully the sprints taking in account what functionality is crucial and what affects the users the most. Used: Core Animation, MagicalRecords, CI/Jenkins, JIRA, MVVM, Agile/Scrum, Cocoapods

iOS Developer at Railwaymen, Kraków

March 2013 - November 2013

SportsBee - This is a social network dedicated to sports fans. I designed the architecture of the application and implemented all of the basic functionality. I was one of the developers who worked on a generic mechanism for a syncing data framework which is used across all iOS projects.

iOS Developer at inFullMobile, Warszawa

December 2011 - March 2013

Demos for the banking industry - My main responsibility was to implement various demos based on a single code base and to keep all of them "alive".

DLD Magazine - I implemented a fancy calendar.

iOS Developer at TouchingIT, Wojnicz

August 2011 - December 2011

Camerapixo - I optimized the photo gallery.

N TV - I implemented an EPG that works on the iPad platform.

iOS Developer at Altconnect, Tarnów

March 2011 - September 2011

I worked on a content management system for iOS. The main goal was to create and gather all useful tools, controllers, views and libraries into a single framework, so they can be easily and quickly used to produce cheap applications for the clients.